Peter Kay

New York, NY • Phone: (551) 233-9232 • e-mail: contact@kaypeter.com

Professional Summary

Dedicated IT professional with over 9 years of accomplished experience in the IT industry with an emphasis on hotel applications. Portfolio of achievement includes increasing efficiency with server-side applications, improve network blueprints, and driving team work performance. Distinguished military background encompassing strong work ethics and commitment to organizational objectives. Proactive manager, team builder, and tactical planner with the ability to hire, train, and motivate top performers. Contributed to the on-going improvement of IT efforts within the Department of Defense through a combination of creativity, initiative, and strong leadership.

Experience

Technical Services Analyst

05/2015 - Present

Loews Hotels & Resorts (Corporate Office) – New York, NY

- Support the ongoing operation and maintenance of the IT infrastructure at 26 properties, 2 data centers, and 2 corporate offices.
- Plan and deliver new IT systems through-out the company. This includes: ADFS 2.0 / Azure AD, CommVault Simpana 11, EMC Isilon.
- Perform back-end maintenance on all servers. This includes PowerShell scripting and Linux Bash commands. Responsible for the decommissioning of 126 Windows 2003 servers and migrating them to 2008/2012R2.
- Migrated 18 Active Directory child domains into one, manageable corporate domain.

IT Manager

05/2014 - 05/2015

The Mark Hotel - New York, NY

- Spearheaded the virtualization project of the property and migrated a total of 32 physical servers to virtual machines on a Colo solution.
- Managed and maintained a total of 150 guest rooms, private residences, and corporate
 offices.
- Trained and managed an IT Department of 2 IT Support Specialists.
- Directly responsible for \$2.5 million dollars' worth of IT equipment.

Intelligence/Network Analyst, Team Leader United States Army – Iraq/Kansas/Korea

06/2005 - 02/2012

- Proficient in military computer systems and aided in the creation of Secret and Top Secret classified networks of 5,000+ users.
- Worked closely with IT personnel to perform quality assurance testing on multiple intelligence systems (MCS, JODIIS, and ASAS-L systems).
- Supervised and trained a team of 8 analysts to be combat ready for US forces in Korea.
- Worked on highly classified SATCOM (Satellite Communication) networks/systems such as DIVN (General Dynamics) and TROJAN systems (ManTech International Corporation) and provided troubleshooting to users.
- Produced over 300+ strategic intelligence reports for high-level intelligence agencies (NSA, CIA, and INSCOM).

Education

• Pennsylvania State University

Bachelor of Science – Information Sciences and Technology Option in Design and Development (Software Development)

Awards and Accomplishments

- Awarded the Bronze Star for meritorious service and exemplary performance in Operation Iraqi Freedom V.
- Awarded the Army Accommodation Medal twice for outstanding performance and performing beyond standards.
- Awarded the Army Achievement Medal for taking initiative and maintaining morale within the work environment.

Proficiencies

- Java, Javascript
- HTML5/CSS
- Mac OS
- Windows 10
- Linux
- VMWare ESXi 6.0
- CommVault Simpana 11
- ADFS 2.0 / Azure AD
- EMC Isilon, OneFS CLI
- Citrix XenDesktop 7.6
- RSA SecurID, MobileIron
- ServiceNow